Ezgi Nazman, Ph.D

Address Sivas, 58, 58000 **Phone** 506 350 2298

E-mail cabukezgi@gmail.com

Twitter https://twitter.com/cabukezgi

Web https://ezgicn.github.io/

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/ezgi-nazman-ph-d-7460b



Focused researcher currently pursuing degree in Statistics and formal education and advanced research experience in multivariate statistics and machine learning. Adept at conducting interviews, literature reviews and data synthesis and analysis. Well-versed creating efficient systems to organize and manage experimental and real data processes.

Skills

Machine Learning	
Data Mining	••••
Multivariate Statistics	••••
Literature reviews	••••
Data collection and analysis	••••
Research reporting	••••
Questionnaire development	••••
Research and analysis	••••
Database searches	••••
Research design	••••

Work History

2019-12 - Current	Research Assistant Cumhuriyet University, Sivas, Turkey
2017-02 - 2019-12	Research Assistant Gazi University, Ankara, Turkey
2016-10 - 2017-01	Research Assistant Cumhuriyet University, Sivas, Turkey
2014-02 - 2016-09	Research Assistant Gazi University, Ankara, Turkey
2013-02 - 2014-02	Research Assistant Cumhuriyet University, Sivas, Turkey

Education

2015-09 - 2019-11	Ph.D.: Statistics
	Gazi University - Ankara
2007-09 - 2012-07	Bachelor of Science: Statistics Ege University - Izmir
2013-09 - 2015-07	Master of Science: Statistics Gazi University - Ankara

Scientific Studies

A. ARTICLES

- **A1.** Olmus H., Bespinar E., **Nazman E**. Performance evaluation of some propensity score matching methods by using binary logistic regression.model. Communications in Statistics-Simulation and Computation, 2019.
- **A2.** Olmus H., **Nazman E.**, Erbas S. Comparison of penalized logistic regression models for rare event case. Communications in Statistics-Simulation and Computation, 2019.
- **A3.** Ünsal M. G. & **Nazman E**. Investigating socio-economic ranking of cities in Turkey using data envelopment analysis (DEA) and linear discriminant analysis (LDA). Annals of Operations Research, vol.0, pp.1-15, 2018.
- **A4. Nazman E.**, Olmus H., Erbas S. Investigating Some Classification Methods to Evaluate Efficiency Results: A Case Study by Using Conjoint Analysis. Journal of Polytechnic, vol.22, pp.687-694, 2019.
- **A5.** Çelik B., Üçok C. Ö. , **Nazman E**. Evaluation of the use of cone beam computed tomography and digital panoramic radiography in the diagnosis of articular eminence and glenoid fossa pneumatization. Selçuk Dental Journal, vol.6, pp.280-286, 2019.
- **A6. Nazman E.**, Olmus H., Erbas S. Investigating Potential Risk Factors Affecting on Suicidal Ideation Among Adolescents in Turkey. Society and Social Work, vol.29, pp.270-291, 2018.
- **A7.** Olmuş H., **Nazman E.**, Erbaş S. An Evaluation of the Two Parameter (2-PL) IRT Models Through a Simulation Study. Gazi Journal of Science, vol.30, pp.235-249, 2017.
- **A8. Nazman E.** & Erbaş S. Evaluation of Group Homogeneity in Gaussian Mixture Models Using Combined Cluster and Discriminant Analysis. Sinop University Journal of Natural Sciences, vol.2, pp.121-132, 2017.

B. ORAL PRESENTATIONS

- **B1.** Aydın O., **Nazman E.** A case study on machine learning classification algorithms in R. satRday Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland, 17 18 May 2019, pp.16
- **B2.** Olmuş H., **Nazman E.**, Erbaş S. Inferences of Firth LR, FLIC and FLAC in terms of bias in rare event case. International Conference on Advances in Statistics, Athens, Greece, 22 24 April 2019, pp.26
- **B3. Nazman E.**, Erbaş S., Olmuş H. Penalized Logistic Regression for Classification: A Case Study for non-OECD Countries. 11th International Statistics Day Conference, Muğla, Turkey, 3 07 October 2018, pp.220
- **B4.** Olmuş H., **Nazman E.**, Erbaş S. Power analysis of Mantel-Haenszel Chi-Square statistic by using several scores for ordered contingency tables. 4th International Researchers, Statisticians and Young Statisticians Congress, İzmir, Turkey, 28 30 April 2018, pp.40
- **B5. Nazman E.**, Erbaş S., Olmuş H. Comparison of link functions in binary response model by using Firth's penalized maximum likelihood estimation method. 4th International Researchers, Statisticians and Young Statisticians Congress, İzmir, Turkey, 28 30 April 2018, pp.95
- **B6.** Şener H., Erbaş S., **Nazman E.** A Comparison on the Ranking of Decision Making Units of Data Envelopment and Linear Discriminant Analysis. 10th International Statistics Congress, Ankara, Turkey, 6 08 December 2017, pp.192
- **B7. Nazman E.**, Erbaş S., Olmuş H. Determining Efficiencies of Different Product Concepts Using Conjoint Analysis(CA) and Data Envelopment Analysis(DEA). 3rd International Researchers, Statisticians and Young Statisticians Congress, Konya, Turkey, 24 26 May 2017, pp.217
- **B8.** Olmuş H., **Nazman E**., Erbaş S. Investigating of Ability Parameter Estimation Using Bootstrap Method for 2-Parameter Logistic Model. 3rd International Researchers, Statisticians and Young Statisticians Congress, Konya, Turkey, 24 - 26 May 2017, pp.259
- **B9. Çabuk E.**, Erbaş S. Determining Homogeneity of Provinces According to the Health Facilities in Turkey. The 8th Conference of Eastern Mediterranean Region of the International Biometric Society, Nevşehir, Turkey, 11 -15 May 2015, pp.52
- **B10.** Dağlıoğlu H., Erbaş S., Çabuk E. The Comparison of Classification Performance of Proportional Odds Model, Decision Tree and Artificial Neural Network Methods for Continuous Independent Variables. 15th International Symposium on Econometrics, Operations research and Statistics, Isparta, Turkey, 22 25 August 2014, pp.535-551.

C. BOOKS

C1. Olmuş H., Erbaş S., **Nazman E.** Statistical Experimental Design with SPSS Aplications for Researchers. Gazi Publishing, Ankara, 2017.

D. REFEREEING

- **D1.** Anatolian Journal of Cardiology, January 2020
- D2. Bitlis Eren University Journal of Natural Sciences, December 2019
- D3. Packt Publishing, 2018
- D4. Journal of Mathematics and Statistics, December 2017
- **D5.** American Journal of Applied Sciences, May 2017

E. GIVEN COURSES

E1. Algorithm Design, Sivas Cumhuriyet University, Department of Statistics&Computer Sciences

F. OTHERS

- **F1.** 6th International Researchers, Statisticians, and Young Statisticians Congress, Organizing Committee Member University of Kyrenia, 23-26th of June, 2021
- F2. İstanbul Data Science Academy, Data Science Summer Bootcamp, May 2020-Current
- F3. World Women Conference, Scientific Advisory Committee Member, Ankara, Turkey, 7-8th of March, 2020

Certifications

2020-05	Big Data, Spark, Machine Learning			
2015-09 Data Mining with R Summer School				
Software	oftware			
	R	0000		
	Python	••••		
	Matlab	••••		
	SQL	••••		
	Latex	••••		
	SPSS	• • • • •		